Guide to the International Association for Cultural Freedom Records 1941-1978
University of Chicago Library
- Series IV: Financial Files, 1951-1968
  - Budget, 1959 (Box 500, Folder 2)
  - Budget, first half, 1960 (Box 500, Folder 3)
  - Budget, 1961-1963 (Box 500, Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1959-1964 (Box 500, Folder 5)
  - Budget, 1959-1964 (Box 500, Folder 6)
  - Budget, 1959-1964 (Box 500, Folder 7)
  - Budget, correspondence with affiliates, 1961-1964 [1/2] (Box 500, Folder 8)
  - Budget, correspondence with affiliates, 1961-1964 [2/2] (Box 500, Folder 9)
  - Budget, correspondence with affiliates, 1961-1963 [1/2] (Box 501, Folder 1)
  - Budget, correspondence with affiliates, 1961-1963 [2/2] (Box 501, Folder 2)
  - Budget, correspondence with affiliates, organization, 1959 (Box 501, Folder 3)
  - Burma, 1957-1960 (Box 501, Folder 4)
  - Busia, K. A., 1960-1962 (Box 501, Folder 5)
  - Cadernos Brasileiros, 1963-1967 (Box 501, Folder 6)
  - Cairo, 1959-1964 (Box 501, Folder 7)
  - Cairo Seminar-Cardinali, 1960-1964, Cairo Seminar, 1960 Calman-Levy (editors), 1963 Campana, Manuel Torres, 1964 Campi, Garcia Maria Th. (Administrative Secretary of the Committee of Writers and Editors), 1962 Cardinali, M., 1964 (Box 501, Folder 8)
  - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1958 (Box 501, Folder 9)
  - Carneiro-Centro de Documentacion, 1962-1966, Carneiro, Luiz O. (Brazilian Committee), 1965-1966 Carreno, M. Suarez, 1964 Carrion, Benjamin, 1965 Carvacho, Victor (Chile), 1965 Cassinelli, Emilio, 1965 Castilla, 1962 Castro's Revolution (Theodore Draper), royalties, 1962-1963 Centro de Documentacion y de Estudios, 1964 (Box 501, Folder 10)
  - Cercle pour la Liberté de la Culture, financial reports, 1962-1963 [1/2] (Box 501, Folder 11)
  - Cercle pour la Liberté de la Culture, financial reports, 1962-1963 [2/2] (Box 501, Folder 12)
  - Cercle pour la Liberté de la Culture, financial reports, 1962 [1/2] (Box 502, Folder 1)
  - Cercle pour la Liberté de la Culture, financial reports, 1962 [2/2] (Box 502, Folder 2)
  - Ceylan-Charities registration, 1957-1964, Ceylan, 1957-1959 Chaami, George, 1962-1963 Chapetot, M., 1963 Charities registration, 1964 (Box 502, Folder 3)
  - Charles, Scott (Paris office), 1957-1960 (Box 502, Folder 4)
  - Charles, Scott (Paris office), 1961 (Box 502, Folder 5)
  - Charles, Scott (Paris office), 1955-1962 [1/2] (Box 502, Folder 6)
  - Charles, Scott (Paris office), 1955-1962 [2/2] (Box 502, Folder 7)
  - Charles, Scott (Paris office), 1962 (Box 502, Folder 8)
  - Charles, Scott (Paris office), 1963 (Box 503, Folder 1)
  - Charles, Scott (Paris office), 1964 (Box 503, Folder 2)
  - Chase, Enrique-Chase Manhattan Bank, 1962-1966, Chase, Enrique (Paraguay), 1964-1966 Chase Manhattan Bank: banking and loans, Scott Charles, Nicolas Nabokov, 1962-1963 Chase Manhattan Bank, 1963-1964 (Box 503, Folder 3)
  - Chase Manhattan Bank, 1961-1964, Chase Manhattan Bank, Paris, 1962-1964 Chase Manhattan Bank, Tokyo, 1961 (Box 503, Folder 4)
  - Checks, unpresented, 1966 (Box 503, Folder 5)
  - Chilean Committee, 1959-1966, Chilean Committee (See also Baraiber, Carvacho, Ogaz), 1959-1963. Chilean Committee, 1962-1966 Chilean Committee; Price Waterhouse financial report, 1962-1966 (Box 503, Folder 6)
  - China-Collins, 1962-1966, China Quarterly, The (See also Barrass, Osborn), 1962-1963 Ciancolo, Umberto (Greece), 1965 City Business Facilities Ltd., 1966 Clarke, Peter E. (Amsterdam), 1962 Coleman, Peter, 1964 Collins Publishers (London), Konstatin Paustovsky's trip to England, 1964 (Box 503, Folder 7)
  - Cologne, 1963 (Box 503, Folder 8)
  - Comite d'Ecrivains et d'Editeurs pour une Entr'aide Intellectuelle Europeenne: articles, minutes of meetings (See also Oprecht), 1964 (Box 503, Folder 9)
  - Committee on Science and Freedom, 1959-1964, C.S.F. Publications Ltd., 1962-1963 C.S.F. Publications Ltd., 1962-1963 C.S.F. Publications Ltd., Price Waterhouse report, 1959-1964 C.S.F. Publications Ltd ., Registration, 1962 (Box 503, Folder 10)
  - Congo, 1959-1963 (Box 503, Folder 11)
  - Copenhagen, 1957-1963 (Box 504, Folder 1)
  - Council-Countinho, 1958-1967, Council on Economic and Cultural Affairs, 1958-1963 Countinho, Afranio (Cadernos Brasileiros), 1964-1967 (Box 504, Folder 2)
  - Crosland-Crossley-Holland, 1958-1963, Crosland, C.A.R. (Planning Committee), 1958 Crosland, C.A.R. (Planning Committee), travel, 1958-1963 Crossley-Holland, Peter, 1961 (Box 504, Folder 3)
  - Cuadernos (See also Gorkin), 1963-1966 (Box 504, Folder 4)
  - Dadoun-d’Arschot, 1958-1965, Dadoun, Odette, 1962-1963 Dakar, Freetown Seminar, 1963 Danielou, Alain, 1960-1961 d'Arschot, Comtess Ruby, 1958-1965 (Box 504, Folder 5)
  - Davenport-Delcerro, 1962-1964, Davenport, Audrey J. (secretary to Edward Shils), 1964 Davis, Aubrey, 1964 De Biase, Regina C., 1964-1966 Decraene, Philip (Le Monde), 1962 Delaney, Beauford, 1964 Delcerro, 1962 (Box 504, Folder 6)
  - de Madariaga, Salvador, 1957-1963 (Box 504, Folder 7)
  - de Rougement, Denis, 1951-1963 (Box 504, Folder 8)
  - Desnaute-Dowuona, 1962-1966, Desnaute (secretary, Institute d'Etudes Congolaises), 1963 de Torre, Guillermo (Buenos Aires), 1964 Devaivre, Marie-France, 1965 Dimock, Edward, 1966 Donaldson, E. K. (Controller, Paris office), 1964-1965 Douek, Victor, 1962 Dowuona, Modj (Freetown conference book editor), 1962-1963 (Box 504, Folder 9)
  - Draper-Ducret, 1960-1964, Draper, Theodore, See also Castro's Revolution, USIS, 1960-1962 Dubourg, Madeleine, 1964 Ducret, Gisele, 1962-1963 (Box 504, Folder 10)
  - Duerden, Dennis, 1961-1964 (Box 504, Folder 11)
  - Dumur-Duquene, 1962-1966, Dumur, Jean, 1962 Duncan, Michael, 1966 Duquene, Marie Therese, 1964 (Box 504, Folder 12)
  - Eastern European Aid-Stipends, 1957-1964, Eastern European Aid, 1957-1961 Eastern European Aid, Bella S. Szasz, 1957-1962 Eastern European Stipends, 1964 (Box 504, Folder 13)
  - East-West Cultural Exchange, 1964 (Box 504, Folder 14)
  - East-West Music Festival, Tokyo, 1959-1963 (Box 504, Folder 15)
  - Economist-El-Shoush, 1962-1964, Economist Newspaper (London), 1963 Editoria Sur S.A. (Buenos Aires), 1964 Edward Joseph Memorial Trust Fund, 1963 El-Shoush, M. L. (Khartoum representative), 1962-1964 (Box 504, Folder 16)
  - Emmanuel-Employment, 1960-1967, Emmanuel, Pierre, 1960-1962 Employment agencies, 1964-1967 (Box 504, Folder 17)
  - Encounters, 1962 (Box 505, Folder 1)
  - Encounters, 1963-1964 (Box 505, Folder 2)
  - Encounters, 1958-1964, Encounters, distribution, 1964 Encounters, Price Waterhouse reports, 1958-1964 (Box 505, Folder 3)
  - Encounters, 1962-1964, Encounters, Price Waterhouse Reports, 1962-1964 Encounters, share capital payment, 1964 (Box 505, Folder 4)
  - Enwowo-Erna, 1960-1964, Enwowu, Ben (Nigeria), 1960 Epoch (Greece), 1964 Erna Low Travel Service, 1962 (Box 505, Folder 5)
  - Executive Committee-Expenditures, 1958-1964, Executive Committee minutes, 1958-1964 Executive Committee minutes, resolution, organization, statutes, articles, members, 1959-1964 Expenditures, 1959 (Box 505, Folder 6)
  - Fanchette-Favrod, 1962-1964, Fanchette, Jean (Paris), 1962-1963 Farrand, Roger (Encounter), 1962-1964 Fauldy, George (London), 1962 Favrod, Charles, 1963 (Box 505, Folder 7)
  - 1961-1963, Ferrand, Roger, (See also Spence), 1962-1963. See also Spence Ferrat, Andre (Centre Africain de Documentation et d'Etudes), 1961 Fiedler, Leslie A., 1963 (Box 505, Folder 8)
  - Financial Organization-Report, 1955-1963, Financial Organization, diagram, undated Financial Report (Paris), Price Waterhouse reports, 1955-1958 Financial Report (Paris), Price Waterhouse reports, 1959 Financial Report (Geneva), supplementary comments, 1963 (Box 505, Folder 9)
  - Financial Reports (Paris), Price Waterhouse reports, (Scandinavian office), 1962-1963 [1/2] (Box 505, Folder 10)
  - Financial Reports (Paris), Price Waterhouse reports, (Scandinavian office), 1962-1963 [2/2] (Box 506, Folder 1)
  - Fitzgerald, Frances (The Paris Review), 1962-1963 (Box 506, Folder 2)
  - Fleischmann, Julius, 1955-1962 (Box 506, Folder 3)
  - Flemming-Flynn, 1964-1967, Flemming, Margo (Survey), 1964 Flynn, B. S. (Secretary, London office), 1965-1967 (Box 506, Folder 4)
  - Ford Foundation, 1959-1962, Ford Foundation, budget estimates, (See also Lowenthal), 1960-1962 Ford Foundation, grant application, 1959 (Box 506, Folder 5)
  - Ford Foundation, A Report to the Ford Foundation, 1957-1958 (Box 506, Folder 6)
  - Ford Foundation, A Report to the Ford Foundation, 1957-1959 (Box 506, Folder 7)
  - Ford Foundation, A Report to the Ford Foundation, 1962 (Box 506, Folder 8)
  - Ford Foundation, A Report to the Ford Foundation, summary, 1960 (Box 506, Folder 9)
  - "Formation of Elites in Latin America" (Montevideo seminar), 1965 (Box 506, Folder 10)
  - Forum, 1960-1961 (Box 506, Folder 11)
  - Forum, (See also Torberg), 1962-1963 (Box 506, Folder 12)
  - Forum, report to M. Josselson (Paris), 1961 (Box 506, Folder 13)
  - Forum Information Services, Price Waterhouse report, (See also Sutton), 1963-1964 (Box 507, Folder 1)
  - Forum Information Services, Price Waterhouse report, 1962-1963 (Box 507, Folder 2)
  - Foyle-Freedom First, 1954-1963, Foyle, W. G. & Co. (London), 1962-1963 Franciosa, Madeleine, 1963 Franco, Alejandro Hamed, 1954 Free Europe Committee (Eugene L. Metz), 1963 Freedom First (M. D. Kim, Bombay), 1963 (Box 507, Folder 3)
  - Freetown Seminar, 1963-1964 (Box 507, Folder 4)
  - Fund for Intellectual Freedom (Arthur Koestler), 1958-1963 (Box 507, Folder 5)
  - Gaeta, Seminar (Italy), "Youth and Its Masks", 1964 (Box 507, Folder 6)
  - Gaspard, Armand, 1961-1964 (Box 507, Folder 7)
  - Gastaud-Globe, 1962-1965, Gastaud, J. (Paris), 1963-1965 Geneva African Institute, 1965 Gilbert, Isabelle, 1962 Giner, Salvador, 1965 Globacnik, Charles, 1963 Globe Travel Service (Pakistan), 1963 (Box 507, Folder 8)
  - Gokhale-Gourevitch, 1962-1966, Gokhale, L. M. (United States), 1962 Gomes, Alain de Obeira, 1965 Gonzalez, Jr., Arturo F. (Time-Life International), 1965 Gordon and Gotch, Ltd. (London), 1964-1966 Gourevitch, Adolphe (Tel-Aviv), 1965 (Box 507, Folder 9)
  - Grants, 1957-1963 (Box 507, Folder 10)
  - Grants, 1957-1961 (Box 507, Folder 11)
  - Grants, 1961-1964 (Box 507, Folder 12)
  - Grants, 1959-1964, Grants, application, 1959 Grants, private application (Helen Luche), 1964 (Box 507, Folder 13)
  - Greece, (See also Cianciolo, Epoch), 1958-1963 (Box 507, Folder 14)
  - Gross-Guibert, 1962-1964, Gross, Babette C., 1962 Guggenheim, Hans, 1964 Guibert, Armand (Paris), 1962 (Box 507, Folder 15)
  - Hall, John (Encounter), 1962 (Box 507, Folder 16)
  - Hamburg, 1958-1964, Hamburg, Germany, 1958-1963 Hamburg Seminar, 1964 (Box 507, Folder 17)
  - Harris-Havana, 1959-1963, Harris, George, 1963 Hartley, Cooper & Co., 1962 Havana, 1959-1961 (Box 507, Folder 18)
  - Haymard-Heller, 1958-1963, Hayward, Max, 1963 Heller (Ford Program), 1958-1961 (Box 507, Folder 19)
  - Hensman-History and Hope, 1960-1965, Hensman, C. R. (The Community Institute), 1961-1963 Heras, Joaquin Gutierrez (Mexico), 1964-1965 Hertz, Pauel, Polish stipend, 1960 Hinden, Rita (Socialist Commentary), 1962 History and Hope (K. A. Jolenski), 1965 (Box 507, Folder 20)
  - Hiwar-Hoang, 1962-1964, Hiwar (Beirut), 1962-1964 Hoang, Van Chi, 1965 (Box 507, Folder 21)
  - The Holmes Foundation, 1957-1963 (Box 507, Folder 22)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1953-1963 (Box 508, Folder 1)
  - Hosking-Howell, 1965-1966, Hosking, Burton & Co., 1966 Howell, Esther (Ilford House), 1965 (Box 508, Folder 2)
  - Hungarian Book Guild-Literary Gazette, 1962-1964, Hungarian Book Guild, 1963-1964 Hungarian Literary Gazette (Irodalmi Ujsag), 1962 (Box 508, Folder 3)
  - Hungarian Literary Gazette (Irodalmi Ujsag), 1963 (Box 508, Folder 4)
  - Hungarian Literary Gazette (Irodalmi Ujsag), liquidation, 1958-1962 (Box 508, Folder 5)
  - Hungarian Literary Gazette (Irodalmi Ujsag), Memorandum and Articles of Association, 1957 (Box 508, Folder 6)
  - Hungarian Literary Gazette-Writer’s Association, 1958-1962, Hungarian Literary Gazette (Irodalmi Ujsag), Price Waterhouse reports, 1958-1962 Hungarian Writers' Association Abroad, 1959 (See also Kemeny) (Box 508, Folder 7)
  - Hunt-Husain, 1956-1964, Hunt, John C., 1956-1962 Husain, Sajjad S., 1964 (Box 508, Folder 8)
  - Ibarguengoitia-Iglesias, 1962-1965, Ibarguengoitia, Jorge (Mexico), 1964 Idrissi, Alami, 1965 Iglesias, Juan, 1962-1965 (Box 508, Folder 9)
  - Indian Committee (Bombay), 1958-1964 (Box 508, Folder 10)
  - Indian Committee (Bombay), financial reports, 1964 (Box 508, Folder 11)
  - Indian Committee (Bombay), Office for Asian Affairs (M. P. Sinha and Prabhakar Podhye), 1960-1963 (Box 508, Folder 12)
  - Indian Committee (Bombay), Paridivala, H. R., 1958-1964 (Box 508, Folder 13)
  - Indian Committee, Sinha, K. K., 1958-1964 (Box 509, Folder 1)
  - Indonesia-Infante, 1958-1963, Indonesia, 1958-1963 Infante, Isidro, 1963 (Box 509, Folder 2)
  - Information Bulletin, Ltd., Price Waterhouse reports, 1958-1961 (Box 509, Folder 3)
  - Information Bulletin, 1962-1963 (Box 509, Folder 4)
  - Institute of Political and Social Studies: Memorandum of Association, 1960 (Box 509, Folder 5)
  - Insurance and Pension Plans, 1962 (Box 509, Folder 6)
  - Insurance and Pension Plans (Box 509, Folder 7)
  - Intergovernmental Committee for European Migration (Geneva), 1954-1959 (Box 509, Folder 8)
  - Intergovernmental Committee for European Migration (Geneva), 1952-1959 (Box 509, Folder 9)
  - International Council, 1957-1964 (Box 509, Folder 10)
  - International Council, 1960-1963 (Box 510, Folder 1)
  - International Music Festival-Society for the History of Ideas, 1960-1965, International Music Festival (Rio de Janeiro), 1962-1963 International Poets Meeting (Berlin), 1964-1965 International Society for the History of Ideas (New York), 1960 (Box 510, Folder 2)
  - Israel, Bronfman's Agency, Ltd., (booksellers), 1957-1963 (Box 510, Folder 3)
  - Israel, Steimatzsky's Agency (booksellers), 1956-1960 (Box 510, Folder 4)
  - Israel, Union Bank of Israel, 1957-1962 (Box 510, Folder 5)
  - Jaffe, Irving, 1959-1963 (Box 510, Folder 6)
  - Japanese Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1958-1963 (Box 510, Folder 7)
  - Japanese Committee for Cultural Freedom, Lowe, Bingham & Thomas audit reports, 1959-1963 (Box 510, Folder 8)
  - Jaramillo-Jargy, 1960-1963, Jaramillo, Manuel Jose (Columbia), 1963 Jargy, Simon (Paris office), 1960-1962 (Box 510, Folder 9)
  - Jelenski, K. A. (Paris office), (See also History and Hope), 1958-1964 (Box 510, Folder 10)
  - Jiyu, Lowe, Bingham & Thomas and Price Waterhouse reports, 1959-1964 (Box 510, Folder 11)
  - Jiyu, Lowe, 1959-1963 (Box 510, Folder 12)
  - Jollivet-Jones-Quartey, 1962-1964, Jollivet, M. Th., 1962-1963 Jones-Quartey, K. A. B., 1963-1964 (Box 510, Folder 13)
  - Josselson, Michael (Geneva office), 1959-1961 (Box 511, Folder 1)
  - Josselson, 1962-1963 (Box 511, Folder 2)
  - Jotikasthira-Journal Vouchers, 1961-1964, Jotikasthira, Chewn (Chief Accountant, Paris office), 1961-1962 Journal vouchers, 1964 (Box 511, Folder 3)
  - Jouvenal-Judd, 1958-1965, Jouvenal, Bertrand de (Planning Committee), 1958-1961 Judd, Gerald (printers), 1965 (Box 511, Folder 4)
  - Kallin-Kats, 1959-1966, Kallin, Anna (researcher, Anthology of Russian Intellectual History), 1965 Katlan, Naim (Le Nouveau Journal), 1966 Kats, Ivan, 1959-1963 (Box 511, Folder 5)
  - Kealey-Kesteloot, 1959-1966, Kealey, Diana (Transcription Feature Service), 1966 Kemeny, George (Hungarian Writers Association Abroad), 1963-1964 Kende, Peter, 1959-1966 Kent Brothers (home furnishers), 1966 The Kenyon Review, 1963 Kersten, Heinz, 1964 Kesteloot, Lagneau (Belgium), 1965 (Box 511, Folder 6)
  - Koestler, Arthur (Planning Committee), (See also Fund for Intellectual Freedom), 1957-1961 (Box 511, Folder 7)
  - Kormos-Kristol, 1958-1966, Kormos, Istvan, 1965 Koston, Paul (bookseller), 1966 Kristol, Irving (Basic Books, Encounter), 1958-1962 (Box 511, Folder 8)
  - Kultura-Lagadere, 1951-1962, Kultura, 1951-1962 Kwame Nkrumah University, 1962 Lagadere, Genevieve, 1962 (Box 511, Folder 9)
  - Lasky, Melvin J., 1958-1964 [1/2] (Box 511, Folder 10)
  - Lasky, Melvin J., 1958-1964 [2/2] (Box 511, Folder 11)
  - Latin America, Financial Reports, 1967-1970 (Box 511, Folder 12)
  - Latin America, Financial Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 511, Folder 13)
  - Latin America, Financial Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 511, Folder 14)
  - Latin American Music Competition-Levete, 1962-1965, Latin American Music Competition, 1962-1963 Laurent, Madeleine, 1965 Ledebur, Madame la Comtesse (Munich), 1963-1964 Ledoux, Woodbridge & Co., 1964 Le Louet, Jean Felix Emile, 1964 Lerner, Abba (Michigan University), 1964 Levete, M. J. (Personnel Administration, Ltd.), 1962 (Box 512, Folder 1)
  - Library of International Studies-London Seminar, 1960-1963, Library of International Studies, 1961-1963 Library of International Studies, Price Waterhouse report, 1963 Lilli Ann (San Francisco), 1960 London Seminar preparation, financial report, 1963 (Box 512, Folder 2)
  - Lopez-Lowenthal, 1957-1965, Lopez, Borras Ricardo, 1965 Lopez-Alvarez, Luis, 1961 Lowenthal, Richard, 1957-1961 (Box 512, Folder 3)
  - Madrid Seminar-Manila Seminar, 1963-1964, Madrid Seminar, 1963-1964 Maltzeff, M. (Paris office), 1964 Manila Seminar Report – 1964, "Religion and Progress in Modern Asia" (Box 512, Folder 4)
  - Manchester (Committee on Science & Freedom (C.S.F.), 1958-1961 (Box 512, Folder 5)
  - Marks-Matshikiza, 1962-1965, Marks and Clark, 1965 Martin Secker & Warburg Ltd. (The Windmill Press), 1962-1964 Marti-Zaro, Pablo, 1962 Mary Stuart Bureau (employment agency), 1964 Mason, H., 1964 Matshikiza, Todd, 1962-1963 (Box 512, Folder 6)
  - Maung-Meidner, 1958-1964, Maung Maung (Director, The Guardian), International Lecture Series, 1958 Maunick, Edouard, 1964 Mazo, F., 1963 Mbari Center (Enugu, Nigeria), 1962-1964 Mbari Center (Oshogbo, Nigeria), 1962-1963 Meidner, Hans, 1964 (Box 512, Folder 7)
  - Memorandum, 1963-1964 (Box 512, Folder 8)
  - Menil-Meray, 1958-1960, Menil, J. de, 1958-1959 Meray, Tibor, 1958-1960 (Box 512, Folder 9)
  - Mercier, Louis (Director, Latin American office in Chile), 1962-1963 (Box 512, Folder 10)
  - Metz-Mexico, 1958-1965, Metz, Eugene L. (Free Europe Committee), (See also Free Europe Committee), 1963 Mexico, (See also Heras, Ibarguengoitia), 1958-1965 (Box 512, Folder 11)
  - Michelovitsch-Ministère des Affaires, 1962-1965, Michelovitsch, Ida M., 1964 Milla, M. B. (Uruguay office), 1964-1965 Minerva, financial report, 1963 Ministère des Affaires Etrangères, 1962-1963 (Box 512, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1963 (Box 512, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1965 (Box 513, Folder 1)
  - Mitchison-Molnar, 1963-1966, Mitchison, Naomi, 1963 Mochtar Buchori, Bagdja N., 1966 Molad (Israel), 1963 Molnar, Miklos (Switzerland), 1965 (Box 513, Folder 2)
  - Der Monat, balances, 1960-1963 (Box 513, Folder 3)
  - Der Monat, correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 513, Folder 4)
  - Der Monat, Price Waterhouse reports, 1959-1965 (Box 513, Folder 5)
  - Monegal-Moreno, 1965-1967, Monegal, Emir Rodriguez, 1965-1967 Moreno, Cesar Fernandez, 1967 (Box 513, Folder 6)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, 1962-1964, Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, London, 1963-1964 Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, New York, 1962-1964 Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, Paris, 1962-1964 (Box 513, Folder 7)
  - Morris-Moussalove, 1959-1962, Morris, John, 1959-1960 Moussalove, Emmanuel, 1962 (Box 513, Folder 8)
  - Mphahlele, Ezekiel (Nairobi), 1963-1964 (Box 513, Folder 9)
  - Mudge-Music Conference and Festival at New Delhi, 1962-1967, Mudge, Stern, Baldwin & Todd, 1962-1963 Mundo Nuevo, 1966-1967 Murena, Hector (Buenos Aires), 1963-1966 Music Conference and Festival at New Delhi, 1962-1965 (Box 513, Folder 10)
  - Nabokov, Nicholas, 1958-1964 (Box 513, Folder 11)
  - Naples-Neufuille, 1957-1964, Naples, Seminar on Problems of Youth, 1964 Narayan, Jayaprakash, 1957-1960 Neufuille, Lawrence E. de (The McMurry Company, New York), 1959-1960 (Box 513, Folder 12)
  - New York State Charities registration, Nkosi, Lewis, 1959-1964 (Box 514, Folder 1)
  - Notes de Service, 1959-1964 (Box 514, Folder 2)
  - Obama-Ogaz, 1959-1964, Obama, Père Jean-Baptiste, 1959-1960 The Observor, 1962 Offices, 1960 Office supplies, 1964 Ogaz, Damaso (Chilean painter), 1963 (Box 514, Folder 3)
  - Olubummo-Osborn, 1962-1965, Olubummo, A. (University College, Nigeria), 1964 Olusola, 1963 Oprecht, Hans (Comite d'Ecrivains et d'Editeurs pour une Entr'aide Europeenne), 1962-1964 Organizacion Regional Intraamericana de Trabajadores, 1965 Osborn, Judy (The China Quarterly), 1962 (Box 514, Folder 4)
  - P. C. Manaktala & Sons Private Ltd., (publishers), audit report, 1965 (Box 514, Folder 5)
  - Pakistan Committee (Syed Ali Ahsan, director), (See also Globe Travel Service), 1957-1963 (Box 514, Folder 6)
  - Pan American-Pardivala, 1963, Pan American World Airways, 1964-1965 Papp, Ibor, 1962 Paraguay Committee (Enrique Chase, Buenos Aires), 1964-1967 Parancs, Janos, 1962 Pardivala, H. R. (Bombay), 1963 (Box 514, Folder 7)
  - Passin, Herbert (University of Washington, Ford Foundation), 1956-1963 (Box 514, Folder 8)
  - Patch-Payment, 1962-1965, Patch, Richard W. (American Universities Field Staff), 1962 Paustousky, Konstantin, 1964-1965 Payment notes, 1963 (Box 514, Folder 9)
  - Payments, Regular, 1st half, 1959 (Box 514, Folder 10)
  - Payments, Regular, 2nd half, 1959 (Box 514, Folder 11)
  - Payments, Regular, 1st half, 1960 (Box 515, Folder 1)
  - Payments, Regular, 2nd half, 1960 (Box 515, Folder 2)
  - Payments, Regular, 1963 (Box 515, Folder 3)
  - Payments, Regular, modifications, 1964 (Box 515, Folder 4)
  - Payrolls, January-May, 1965 (Box 515, Folder 5)
  - Payrolls, June-August, 1965 (Box 515, Folder 6)
  - Payrolls, September-December, 1965 (Box 515, Folder 6)
  - Pazos-Periodicals, 1962-1966, Pazos, Javier (Liborio), 1964 Pendered, Philip, 1964 Pendulo (Paraguay), 1965-1966 Penguin Books Ltd (England), 1966 Periodicals, subsidies, 1962 (Box 515, Folder 8)
  - Personnel, 1962-1963 (Box 515, Folder 9)
  - Personnel, 1963 (Box 516, Folder 1)
  - Peru, 1962-1967 (Box 516, Folder 2)
  - Peruvian Committee (Luis Alberto Sanchez, Executive President), 1958-1963 (Box 516, Folder 3)
  - Peters-Phillip Hill, 1958-1962, Peters, Ann (Forum Service, London), 1962 Philharmonia Hungarica (Vienna), financial statements, 1958 Phillip Hill, Hissinson, Erlangers, Ltd. (A. R. Fish, manager), 1962 (Box 516, Folder 4)
  - Phillipines (Manila office), 1960-1963 (Box 516, Folder 5)
  - Phillips-Pinon, 1964-1967, Phillips, William, 1964 Piazza, Luis Guillermo, 1965-1967 Pinon, Nelida Cuinas (Brazilian Committee), 1964-1965 (Box 516, Folder 6)
  - Polanyi, Michael (Oxford, University of Manchester), 1957-1962 (Box 516, Folder 7)
  - Politi-Preuves, 1959-1965, Politi, Maurice, 1965 Pond, Elizabeth, 1964 Porter, Arthur T., 1962 Preuves (Paris), debits, (See also Boulain, Dumar), 1959-1960 (Box 516, Folder 8)
  - Price Waterhouse Reports, 1957-1963, Price Waterhouse Reports, summary, 1958-1963 Price Waterhouse Reports, London, 1957-1963 (Box 516, Folder 9)
  - Price Waterhouse Reports, Paris, 1962 (Box 516, Folder 10)
  - Price Waterhouse-Publications, 1959-1964, Price Waterhouse Reports, Paris, 1963-1964 Price Waterhouse Reports, Zurich, 1959-1960 Projects, 1959-1960 Puben, Jose, 1966 Publications, audits, 1962-1963 (Box 516, Folder 11)
  - Quest-Quester, 1956-1965, Quest (publication of the Indian Committee), 1956-1964 Quester, George H. (Harvard University), 1965 (Box 517, Folder 1)
  - Rabb-Rasai, 1958-1964, Rabb Charitable Foundation, Sydney and Esther, 1963 Raditza, Bogdan, 1958-1960 Raduget, Andre, 1964 Rajsfus, Olga, 1963 Random House, Inc. (Lillian Scott), 1962 Rasai, Davoud (New York), 1961-1962 (Box 517, Folder 2)
  - Receipts and Disbursements, Geneva, overview, 1955-1962 (Box 517, Folder 3)